

Soohwan Kim

ALRESEARCH ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ENGINEER

16F, Gangnam-daero 382 Merits Tower, Gangnam-gu, Seoul, 06232, Korea

□ (+82) 10-4564-4668 | 🗷 kaki.ai@tunib.ai | 🏕 sooftware.github.io | 🖸 sooftware | 🛅 Soo-hwan

"I dream of talking to artificial intelligence."

About Me

Current Co-founder and AI Research Engineer of TUNiB Inc. Former AI Research Engineer at Kakao Brain. I majored in Electronic & Communication Engineering and minored in Data Science at Kwangwoon university. My research interests include technologies for human-machine interaction, such as automatic speech recognition, speech synthesis, and open-domain dialogue. I enjoy software development and sometimes like to write my knowledge or thoughts. I want to be helpful to others through open source. You can check my github page (http://github.com/sooftware) to see what I am currently up to.

Education

Kwangwoon University

Seoul. South Korea

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING, MAJOR IN ELCOMM, MINOR IN DATA SCIENCE

Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2021

- Major GPA: 3.90 / 4.5 / Total GPA: 3.67 / 4.5
- Major/Minor Courses: Capstone Design I-II, AI & Speech Signal Processing, Software Design, Machine Learning, Computer Architecture, Operating System, Data Structure & Algorithm, Data Mining, Network Programming, IoT System Design, Big Data Language, Big Data Processing & Application, Database, Digital Signal Processing, Statistical application, Object-Oriented Programming, Object-Oriented Programming Practice, Open-Source Software, System Programming, C programming, Mobile Programming, Data Communication, Computer Network, Basic Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Electronic Circuit Theory I-II, Digital Logic, Physics Electronic Technology, Engineering Math I-II, Probability and Irregular Signaling Theory, Probability and Statistics

Professional Experience

TUNIB Inc.Gangnam, Seoul

Co-founder, Al Research Engineer

Mar. 2021 - Present

- Create conversational digital humans who people emotionally engage with.
- Research and develop the latest NLP technology.
- Webpage: www.tunib.ai [link]

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

AI RESEARCH ENGINEER

Nov. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- Research & develop speech and natural language processing fields
- Development PORORO: Platform Of neuRal mOdels for natuRal language prOcessing [link]

Internships _____

Kakao Brain Pangyo, Gyunggi

AI RESEARCH INTERN

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Research & Development of automatic speech recognition models
- Development of multilingual speech synthesis model with support for twelve Languages

Spoken Language Lab (of Sogang Univ.)

Mapo, Seoul

Undergraduate Researcher

Apr. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Studies speech recognition techniques based on various machine learning algorithms (e.g. deep learning). [link]
- Research End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition Models

Military Service _____

ROKMC Served and discharged from Republic of Korea Marine Corps as Signaller, Sergeant, 2015.09 - 2017.06

Publication

- 2021 KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition, ELSEVIER, SIMPAC
- 2020 End-to-End Speech Recognition Models in English, Korean and Chinese, Bachelor's Graduation Thesis

Project Experience

PORORO: Platform Of neuRal mOdels for natuRal language prOcessing

Kakao Brain

MAINTAINER, TEAM MEMBER

Sep. 2020 - Mar. 2021

- PORORO performs Natural Language Processing and Speech-related tasks. [link]
- It is easy to solve various subtasks in the natural language and speech processing field by simply passing the task name.

Multilingual Text-To-Speech

Kakao Brain Oct. 2020 - Feb. 2021

THE PERSON IN CHARGE • Development of a model that supports multilingual Text-To-Speech.

· Supports 11 multi-language, Cross-lingual Voice Style Transfer, and Code-Switching functions. [link]

English, Chinese, and Korean End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition

Kakao Brain

THE PERSON IN CHARGE

Aug. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Listen, Attend and Spell, Transformer, and Wav2vec 2.0 Model experiments
- · Speech recognition speecd and performance comparison by output-units (character, grapheme, etc.)

KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition

Kwanawoon Univ. Jan. 2020 - Feb. 2021

TEAM LEADER

- · Modular and extensible end-to-end Korean automatic speech recognition (ASR) toolkit
- It is the most popular Korean speech recognition task in gitHub. [link]

Extracurricular Activity

Speech Paper Reading

Study

GROUP MEMBER

Dec. 2020 - Present

- · Weekly meeting where people who work in the field of Speech gather and read papers.
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

NLP Paper Reading Study

GROUP MEMBER Sep. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- · Kakao Brain Natural Language Processing Team's weekly paper reading study
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

Technical Blog Blog

WRITER Aug. 2018 - Present

- Technical posting of deep learning, programming, signal processing, paper review etc.
- · Having more than 100 subscribers and an average of 200 visitors a day [link] [link]

Skills

Python, Java, C/C++, Shell Script, SQL, Android, Arduino, Assembly, HTML **Programming**

Deep Learning PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Fairseq, Transformers, PyTorchLightning, Wav2letter, Faiss, Hydra

Data Analysis Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, NLTK

Awards & Honors

AWARDS

2020.11 President's Award (1st Place)), Kwangwoon Engineering Festival
---------------------------------------	-----------------------------------

2020.11 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon Engineering Festival

2019.10 Finalist (12th Place), Naver A.I Hackathon - Speech

2019.09 Finalist, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Fall

2019.04 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Spring

2018.08 Best Award, Samsung Multi-Campus in Java-based Algorithm for SW Development

Honors

2020.03	School Representative	, 5G-based ICT	Convergence Ser	vice Idea Contest
---------	-----------------------	----------------	-----------------	-------------------

2020.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship

2019.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.09 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University

2018.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University